# Michał Wadowski

# Senior Java Developer

Michał is software development passionate with over 14 years of experience in various technologies and languages. He has been working in Java oriented projects for over 4 years using Spring Boot technologies. He values clean code, TDD and other good programming practices.

# **Professional experience**

Mindbox S.A.

HSBC Service Delivery (Polska) Sp. z o.o.

08.2022 - 06.2024

Senior Java Developer

Developing "Strategic Financial Planning" - internal business application in Java 8, 11, 17 using Spring Boot in microservices architecture. PostgreSQL/Oracle, ReactJS and Jenkins was

also used in project.

Orange Polska S.A.

Java Developer

02.2022 - 07.2022

Developing microservices for streaming platform using Kafka, MongoDB and Java

Reactor

Orange Polska S.A.

Java Developer

02.2021 - 07.2022

Developing Eclipse Leshan library <a href="https://www.eclipse.org/leshan">https://www.eclipse.org/leshan</a> for IoT communication protocol (Lightweight M2M).

Orange Polska S.A.

Java Developer

08.2020 - 07.2022

Developing research application ThingIn The City using Spring Boot and PostgreSQL technologies.

Orange Polska S.A.

**Android Developer** 

03.2020 - 01.2021

Developing mobile application for technicians using Live Objects platform

<a href="https://liveobjects.orange-business.com">https://liveobjects.orange-business.com</a> with

Android Studio in Java and Kotlin languages.

As a development model was used SCRUM

framework.

Awans Sp. z o. o.

06.2014 - 02.2020

**Full-stack Developer** 

Developing <a href="https://awanser.pl">https://awanser.pl</a> business

platform using technologies:

Backend: PHP and CakePHP framework,

PostgreSQL database system Frontend: ReactJS with Redux and Ecmascript 6, CSS, LESS and SCSS

## Contact

#### **Address**

Warsaw, Poland

#### **Phone**

+48 796 334 459

#### E-mail

wadosm@gmail.com

#### Github

https://github.com/Michal-Wadowski

# **Experience and knowledge**

#### Programming languages / technologies

Java: Spring Boot, JUnit, Hibernate, Lombok, Java Reactor, Kafka

#### **Databases**

PostgreSQL with PL/pgSQL, MySQL, Oracle, MongoDB

#### Other tools

Maven, GIT, Docker compose, Jenkins

## **Good practices**

TDD, DDD, Clean architecture, software design patterns

#### IDE

IntelliJ IDEA

## **Operating systems**

Linux, Windows

#### **Software Development Model**

**SCRUM** 

#### Languages and technologies in past

Android in Kotlin

Javasript: ECMAScript 6, JSX, ReactJS,

Redux, ¡Query

Python: NUMPY, Keras

C, C++

Zeto Olsztyn Sp. z o. o.

Java Developer

Developing integration layer with ePUAP system in Java and PostgreSQL + PL/pgSQL

Zeto Olsztyn Sp. z o. o.

**Software Developer** 

10.2011 - 12.2012

01.2013 - 05.2014

Developing of business application in Delphi and, PostgreSQL + PL/pgSQL

iDelfi Polska Sp. z o. o.

Full-stack Developer

11.2009 - 12.2010

Developing internet application for HACCP management in technologies: Ruby on Rails, Javascript, ¡Query, MySQL

# **Training**

March 2022

Professional Scrum Developer <u>I (PSD I)</u>

## **Education**

2009 - 2011

University of Warmia and Mazury in Olsztyn

Field of study: Computer science

M. Sc.

2005 - 2008

University of Warmia and Mazury in Olsztyn

Field of study: Computer systems

Undergraduate course

### Courses

Creating  $\mu$ Services using Spring Cloud and Docker

https://www.altkomakademia.pl

Spring Framework II

https://www.altkomakademia.pl

Pragmatic refactoring using DDD techniques

https://bottega.com.pl

Clean Code in Java

https://pragmatists.thinkific.com

**Test-Driven Development in practice** 

https://pragmatists.thinkific.com

# **Useful characteristics**

Writing good quality code

Experienced in working with legacy systems

IT technologies quick learner

Teamwork skills

Independence and responsibility

# Languages

**Polish** 

Native

**English** 

В2

# **Passions & hobbies**

Programming microcontrollers and developing electronic circuits

Building and training artificial neural networks

Developing applications and devices for own needs

Astronomy, quantum physics and science in general

